okay guys here's an awesome glute Bridge
variation that I want you guys to try
and it's I'm calling it frog pumps and
um I've I thought of it um due to like a
combination of what I know about glute
biomechanics and then also what I've
seen from other strength coaches over
the years for example just recently Ben
Bruno wrote a guest blog for me saying
you should you know keep keep your your
neck your head and neck a little bit
flexed during the hip thrust and it
improves your spinal position increases
glute activation another strength coach
Years Ago by the name of Smitty started
having his his athletes putting their
feet together like this and doing hip
thrust and he was a big fan of that now
let's think about what these cues do
I'll explain the the postural cues that
you're going to use and I'll explain why
they work so uh first of all when you
flex your knees you shorten the
hamstrings you take them out of it so
the more Flex the knee the less it's
going to produce Force so the glutes
have to produce the hip extension
torque um when you abduct the hip and
extra rotate the hip this increases
glute activity finally when you post
your tilt the pelvis that increases
glute activity as well and it takes the
Erectors out of the equation so you're
going to here's what you're going to do
get down in the glute Bridge position
now I don't want you like this okay this
is the standard glute Bridge position
what I want you to do is flatten out the
Lumar spine and then tuck your chin all
the way so your chin is touching your
chest all right dig your elbows into the
ground and make fists so here's and then
oh you're going to put your feet
together like this and don't put them
out here get them as far back or towards
your butt as you can so this here is the
starting position keep your chin at your
chest keep your low back flat your knees
out and then from here just
P just like that now um I did two sets
of 30 earlier today today and my glutes
were totally pumped up this is an
awesome glute activation drill that you
can do just with body weight it works
very well it's great for people it's a
great glute activation drill for anyone
but especially for those who have
trouble firing their glutes with hip
thrust or even with squats or deadlifts
or anything else um this is a good
regression and so uh you can give them
this and then hopefully they can learn
to you know activate their glutes to a
greater degree when they perform other
movements as well but uh you can do this
as a glute activation drill before you
do your other exercises or you can do it
as its own little workout like I said I
did two sets of 30 uh earlier today and
my glutes were pumped up I got a big
burn it works great so please give it a
try let me know what you think